<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Saif Bari on Portfolio</title>
    <link>//saifbari.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Saif Bari on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//saifbari.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TEST POST</title>
      <link>//saifbari.com/blog/lorem-markdownum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//saifbari.com/blog/lorem-markdownum/</guid>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <description>
          <![CDATA[ 
          
          
            <p>
              <img align="left" hspace="5" src="/blog/lorem-markdownum/images/aaron-burden-AXqMy8MSSdk-unsplash_hubbfe6d9ef68d83c7b8ac0a6954f2118c_2893721_0x550_resize_q100_h2_box.webp"/>
            </p>
          
          <p>TEST POST</p>
<hr>
<p>Image: <a href="https://unsplash.com/@aaronburden" title="https://unsplash.com/@aaronburden" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://unsplash.com/@aaronburden</a></p>

          
          
          
          
          
          ]]>
      </description>


    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Resume</title>
      <link>//saifbari.com/cloud-resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 10:53:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//saifbari.com/cloud-resume/</guid>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <description>
          <![CDATA[ 
          
          
<div style="text-align: center;">


<p><em>Inspired by the <a href="https://cloudresumechallenge.dev/docs/the-challenge/aws/" title="AWS Cloud Resume Challenge" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">AWS Cloud Resume Challenge</a></em></p>

</div>



<div style="text-align: center;">


<h2 id="certifications" class="link-owner">
  <a href="//saifbari.com/saifbari.com/cloud-resume/#certifications" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Certifications
</h2><p>
</div>



<div style="display: flex; justify-content: space-around;">


 

    <a href="https://www.credly.com/badges/db4955c2-3870-47ba-803c-fb1a026b9851/public_url"> 
        <img src="//saifbari.com/images/SysOpsBadge_hu3720bb41cf4d6ef4814c0161c078ee69_61949_250x0_resize_box_3.png" alt="Image Alt Text" />
    </a> 





 

    <a href="https://www.credly.com/badges/3e2a0155-7c5e-4243-acd3-34c4e6c1c195/public_url"> 
        <img src="//saifbari.com/images/SolutionsArchitectBadge_huab3f0e60d9213c939db7af5831f32e09_60764_250x0_resize_box_3.png" alt="Image Alt Text" />
    </a> 



</div>

</p>

<div style="text-align: center;">


<h2 id="experience" class="link-owner">
  <a href="//saifbari.com/saifbari.com/cloud-resume/#experience" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Professional Experience
</h2><p>
</div>


<strong>Systems Administrator, Technical Solutions Engineer, IT Consultant</strong><br>
<em>Fixed Computing</em><br>
<em>Aug 2014 - Present</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Over a seven-year period, designed and executed comprehensive technical infrastructures for three separate graduate film program sites for Mount Saint Mary’s University.
<ul>
<li>Managed a broad scope that included low-voltage, network infrastructure, end-user devices, on-premise servers, cloud systems, software management, technical support, multimedia studios, AV systems, and educational labs.</li>
<li>Demonstrated commitment to operational excellence, maintaining 100% uptime and consistently meeting Service Level Agreement (SLA) standards through the diligent support of systems, crucial business operations, and end-user requirements.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Over a four-year period, provided technical support and consultation to the advertising firm, Storyboards Inc, resolving persistent issues and improving system performance, contributing to increased operational efficiency.
<ul>
<li>Strategically upgraded and optimized on-premises network infrastructure, servers, and end-user devices, boosting performance and operational capabilities.</li>
<li>Facilitated the migration of technical assets to Google Workspaces, assisting the organization&rsquo;s transition to remote work.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Over a two-year period, executed network infrastructure and security systems upgrades for a business owner operating two All-State insurance offices and a coffee shop.
<ul>
<li>Additionally, provided robust Windows end-user support, enhancing system functionality and user experience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Technical Support Manager of Desktop and Media Services</strong><br>
<em>Mount Saint Mary&rsquo;s University</em><br>
<em>2014-2017</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Led the Desktop Support, Help Desk Call Center, and AV/Media Departments, supporting an enterprise environment with 500 end-users, 1,800 computers, 1,000 mobile devices, AV systems, peripherals, and several servers across two campuses. Delivered 24/7/365 Level 1, 2, and 3 support.</li>
<li>Developed and continually optimized a technical support knowledge base and standard operating procedures, facilitating the organization&rsquo;s transition to a fully in-house IT structure.</li>
<li>Supervised a team of 5 full-time technicians and 50 student workers, efficiently managing weekend and on-call coverage.</li>
<li>Enhanced IT service delivery by reducing ticket queues by 90% and significantly improving response and ticket resolution times.</li>
<li>Facilitated end-user support for newly implemented SaaS products during an institution-wide digital transformation initiative.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>IT Analyst</strong><br>
<em>Mount Saint Mary&rsquo;s University</em><br>
<em>2013-2014</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Provided comprehensive technical support to faculty, staff, and students, troubleshooting and resolving a wide array of software and hardware issues both remotely and on-site.</li>
<li>Executed hardware deployment, upgrades, configuration, optimization and maintenance across computers, servers, printers, and venue sites.</li>
<li>Contributed to school-wide software upgrades and installations, ensuring seamless integration and minimal disruption.</li>
<li>Diagnosed and resolved A/V issues across multiple event venues, maintaining optimal performance.</li>
<li>Maintained meticulous records of user issues and resolutions in ServiceNow, routing complex cases to the appropriate departments.</li>
<li>Troubleshot and resolved network issues related to both LAN and WAN, enhancing network reliability.</li>
<li>Assisted in inventory management, ensuring accurate tracking of assets and licenses.</li>
<li>Supported the maintenance, upgrades, and setup of AV equipment managed through Utelogy.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>IT Support Specialist</strong><br>
<em>UC San Diego</em><br>
<em>2007-2012</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Authored technical reports and created comprehensive user manuals, tutorials, and knowledge base articles, simplifying complex concepts for broad audiences.</li>
<li>Delivered robust technical support to end-users, conducting help desk functions, client issue triage, computer and peripheral device maintenance, and leveraging remote administration tools for technical support.</li>
<li>Monitored incident and request ticket queues, prioritizing based on severity and department SLAs to expedite resolution.</li>
<li>Managed the updating, installation, and repair of diverse information systems equipment, including specialized clinical products, hardware components, and network devices.</li>
<li>Conducted client training sessions on system usage, promoting user competence and self-sufficiency.</li>
</ul>

<div style="text-align: center;">


<h2 id="skills" class="link-owner">
  <a href="//saifbari.com/saifbari.com/cloud-resume/#skills" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Skills
</h2>
</div>


<p><strong>OS</strong><br>
MacOS, Windows, Linux<br>
<strong>Cloud</strong><br>
AWS - EC2, Lambda, API Gateway, RDS, S3, DynamoDB, CloudWatch, CloudFront, EFS, SNS, SQS, Route53<br>
<strong>IaC</strong><br>
Terraform, AWS CloudFormation, Docker, AWS SAM<br>
<strong>Programming Languages</strong><br>
Shell, Python, JavaScript, HTML/CSS<br>
<strong>Databases</strong><br>
SQL/Postgres, NoSQL<br>
<strong>CI/CD</strong><br>
Github, Github Actions<br>
<strong>Network</strong><br>
Cisco, SonicWall, Netgear<br>
<strong>MDM</strong><br>
JAMF, SCCM, PDQ Deploy &amp; Inventory<br>
<strong>SaaS</strong><br>
Google Workspaces, Office365, ServiceNow, Avid, Adobe, ConnectWise, Slack</p>

<div style="text-align: center;">


<h2 id="education" class="link-owner">
  <a href="//saifbari.com/saifbari.com/cloud-resume/#education" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Education
</h2><p>
</div>


<strong>UC San Diego</strong><br>
<em>2007-2011</em><br>
Bachelors, ICAM (Interdisciplinary Computing and the Arts)</p>
<div style="text-align: center;">
    <div>Visitor Count:</div>
    <div><span id="visitor-counter"></span></div>
  </div>
  




          
          
          
          
          
          ]]>
      </description>


    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//saifbari.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//saifbari.com/about/</guid>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <description>
          <![CDATA[ 
          
          <p>Hello! As an IT professional, I&rsquo;ve built a diverse career managing, supporting, and optimizing on-premise systems. My experience spans roles including System Administrator, IT Consultant, Technical Support, and IT Manager across various industries such as Education, Entertainment, Advertising, Healthcare, and Insurance.</p>
<p>While I&rsquo;ve generally worked in traditional IT environments, I&rsquo;m now excited to pivot my career towards the cloud. I&rsquo;ve been proactively developing my skills in AWS, programming, and systems architecture by working on portfolio projects and acquiring certifications to prepare for this transition. My goal is to leverage my solid IT foundation into a new role in DevOps, Cloud Engineering, Cloud Administration, or Site Reliability Engineering, where I can contribute to designing, implementing, and managing robust cloud-based solutions.</p>
<p>Beyond my professional pursuits, I enjoy hiking, kettlebell workouts, and video gaming. In addition to my tech-focused career, I have a <a href="https://www.fixedmastering.com" title="small side business as an audio mastering engineer" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">small side business as an audio mastering engineer</a>. This venture not only reflects my diverse interests but is also structured in a way that allows me ample time to stay committed to my primary passion - technology.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m looking forward to exploring new opportunities in this space and contributing to the future of technology. Let&rsquo;s connect and see how we can make this happen together!</p>

          
          
          
          
          
          ]]>
      </description>


    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>